Samuel M. Corwin

Phone: (719) 502-6693 Email: samuelcorwin4@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Renewable energy market and policy analyst with strong research and communication skills (in English and Mandarin Chinese). Motivated to use proven qualitative and quantitative problem-solving abilities to be part of a team working to develop and implement clean energy solutions.

Professional Experience

Fulbright U.S. Student Program, Nanjing, China

Personal Website: https://smcorwin.github.io/

Fulbright Fellow, Fall 2017-present

Researching the development of China's domestic solar PV energy market based on analysis of electricity market reforms, policy changes, and local government support. Investigating the prevalence of local protectionism by comparing provincial-level manufacturing output, installation subsidies and statistics. Interviewing stakeholders to compile a report about the role of local governments in China's solar PV market. Report to be completed in Aug. 2018.

Asia Society Northern California, Nanjing, China

Co-Author and Analyst, Nov. 2017-present

Co-authoring a report on clean technology collaboration between the U.S. and China. Responsible for a section on case studies regarding commercial clean technology collaboration, with a focus on market access, finance and investment, and research and development. Analyzing barriers to entry for private Chinese and American companies seeking to access each other's market. Investigating financing and investment channels for clean technology collaboration.

Natural Resources Defense Council (NRDC), Washington, D.C., *Energy Efficiency for All (EEFA) Fellow*, Summer 2016 Researched and identified gaps in EEFA, a program designed to expand access to energy efficiency upgrades in affordable multifamily housing. Proposed and completed a 30-page report examining how to integrate solar PV with energy efficiency upgrades by analyzing barriers, policy and financial opportunities, and evaluating EEFA states for pilot projects. Presented findings to EEFA staff and partner organizations to guide implementation.

Clean Energy Associates (CEA), Shanghai, China

Supply Chain Management Intern, Fall 2015

Produced an analysis and production recommendation of a solar module metallization and cell interconnect technology based on efficiency improvements and market compatibility. Completed competitive analysis research to help CEA identify major competitors and their business models. Developed strategic planning resources, focusing on policy in Japan and Mexico. Developed expertise in global solar supply chain, solar cell technology, and competitive analysis.

Population Connection, Washington, D.C.

Population Education Stanback Fellow, Summer 2015

Developed and researched content for environmental education resources (https://goo.gl/f0xKk1). Helped write and create curriculum for high school environmental classes, wrote blog posts and prepared educational workshops.

Other Relevant Experience

Energy Reports and Carbon Pricing, Bass Connections, Duke University

Fall 2016-Spring 2017

Lead author on a report detailing recommendations presented to Duke's Executive VP about an internal carbon pricing model and educational programs. Based on expertise gained related to carbon pricing and capital investment decision-making, worked with a multidisciplinary team of faculty and students to make recommendations focusing on reducing on-campus energy consumption. Created departmental energy reports to convey energy consumption.

Duke University Campus Sustainability Committee, Combined Heat and Power (CHP) Plant Subcommittee Spring 2017 Member of a multidisciplinary group of on-campus stakeholders, which made a recommendation to Duke's Board of Trustees on a proposed on-campus 21 MW CHP plant. Contributed to evaluation of financial feasibility, the use of biogas, and potential alternatives using knowledge of the economics of electrical generation, CHP plants, and campus power networks.

Education

Harbin Institute of Technology, Harbin, China

July-Oct.2017

Graduated: May 2017

Chinese language immersion with environmental/renewable energy focus

Duke University, Durham, NC | GPA: 3.73

Double Major: Environmental Science/Policy, Asian & Middle Eastern Studies (Chinese concentration)

- Environmental Science Department Independent Study: "The Growth and Development of China's Solar PV Market". Examined the policy drivers behind the development of China's international and domestic solar photovoltaic (PV) market, the effect on global solar PV prices, and the impact on the solar markets of Japan, Germany, and the U.S.
- Fudan University (Boston University), Shanghai, China: advanced Chinese with environmental internship

Fall 2015

Duke Summer in China, Beijing, China: Chinese language immersion program | GPA: 3.7

Summer 2014

Honors and Awards

- J. William Fulbright Foreign Scholarship for China, 2017-2018; CET-Harbin Critical Language Enhancement Award, 2017
- Duke University Fall 2013 Dean's List, Fall 2014 Dean's List, Spring 2016 Dean's List with Distinction
- Air Academy High School Senior Speaker; graduated Summa Cum Laude (4.6+ GPA), 2013
- 2012 Boulder Marathon: finished first place in the 16-19 age group

Additional Information

- Foreign Languages: Advanced Mandarin Chinese (reading, speaking, and writing), Proficient Spanish
- Strengths: Leadership and teamwork ability; creativity; excellent presentation and written communication skills
- Skilled in: Python, Microsoft Office, Adobe Premier Elements, Photoshop, Final Cut Pro, Photography, and Video
- Interests: Photography/digital editing, snowboarding, running, hiking, sports, and volunteer work